You have to admit, we've brought a diverse
group of opinions today. And as Governor
Cox has said, we do know how to disagree
better in Utah. And I assure you, I have
not slept well for four years balancing
all of these different requirements, but
we're doing a good job. I am really
excited to announce the next person who's
going to address us, Jeremy Grant. So he's
managing director in Venable, Venable's
LLP technology and innovation practice.
this. But I think most interestingly and
most importantly, he coordinates the
Better Identity Coalition and has been
working in the space for decades and is
going to be an extremely valuable member
as we move forward to learn how to work
with those he represents. Thanks, Jeremy.
Hey, thank you, Chris, for the invitation
to come out and great meeting so many of
you today and also seeing a few old
friends. So Better Identity Coalition, I
just want to say from the start, we're
really thrilled to see this today and that
if there's one thing we have been
consistently calling for since the
coalition was first formed in 2018 and
published our initial policy blueprint.
It's that as a country and an individual
state, we need to be thinking about this
constructively and strategically. We have
not had a strategy for digital identity in
the US that outlines what good looks like
and how to get there or for that matter
what the bad outcomes could look like and
how to avoid them since the last time we
had a strategy was one that I ran. It was
an Obama administration initiative that
was launched in 2011 that was called the
National Strategy for Trusted Identities
in Cyberspace. And there were some things
that worked well in that program and some
things that didn't. But I think one thing
that everybody should take away is that
for the last 10 years as our peers across
the globe are all thinking about identity
different ways and they're thinking about
it strategically, we've been tackling it
really on sort of a siloed approach,
something for age verification, something
for government login, something perhaps
for KYC for banks, but there hasn't been a
holistic approach. And so this is what
we've been, in some cases I would say,
begging policymakers to take on. And so
seeing what Utah has done and other so
many officials today from governor's
offices and state legislatures and other
states, it's awesome to see. In terms of
who we are, so I mentioned my time running
the NSTIC initiative. I was also dual
-hatted as the guy who led the digital
identity research and standards team at
NIST in the DC area and helped launch the
privacy engineering team around identity
that still does a lot of great projects
today on that front. The coalition is an
interesting group. So we've got big tech
giants that some of whom people have been
calling into question what they want
today. So Apple's a member of Google,
Microsoft. We also have companies that
help pioneered or led efforts in
decentralized or self-sovereign identity
companies like Gen Digital or Block. The
coalition's really driven, however, by
those that I would say are on the buy side
of identity. Our origin story was around
this time eight years ago, there was a
little breach that happened that wasn't in
the news of all from a company called
Equifax where they lost 141 million social
security numbers and it also raised some
bigger concerns around identity in that
the default way we would prove who we were
online say to open a bank account or apply
for a government service was to use
knowledge-based verification. Here's five
questions from your credit report or you
can answer them. It must be you. Well, we
all know that hasn't been true for a long
time given all the breaches we've had. And
so we were largely founded by the buyers
of identity who just need better solutions
to run their businesses. So think
companies in banking, payments, fintech,
healthcare, telecom. We have some of the
vendors at the table as well, but it's a
pretty motley assortment and the companies
probably don't agree on much other than we
should be thinking about digital identity
strategically. I called Jay in 2021 when
he published his paper, which is a great
read by the way on the risks of digital ID
because he talked a lot about the shadowy
identity industrial complex that was
pushing for things like mobile driver's
licenses. And I said, I think I'm running
that. But the good news is we mostly agree
with you on the issues that are in the
paper. We actually think they did an
amazing job at highlighting the risks to
digital ID along with potential decisions
in terms of architecture or policy on how
you could be designing things like MDLs.
Chang was mentioning before the great work
that's happening at NIST right now through
their National Cybersecurity Center of
Excellence to come up with a family of
standards and our playbook of standards
and best practices to help states
including you know the folks who are here
set a high bar for security and privacy
and ensure interoperability. Five states
are participating alongside Apple and
Google and seven banks and a lot of other
big players right now. It's a great
example of how you can actually get
interest from all across the board to
collaborate on you know achieving good
outcomes here. So you know we're out there
you know quite a bit sometimes excited
about MDLs not because we think the DMVs
are the most awesome place for identity to
be housed. But it is at the end of the
day, the one place that most adult
Americans go through and prove where they
are in person to get either a driver's
license or a non-driver state ID card. And
so we think as we look to get away from
companies who are basically trying to
hoover up a bunch of data on us and guess
who we are. Look, I live in DC. I went to
the DMV three years ago to get my real ID
driver's license. It was not a pleasant
experience. I've gone through a similar
process with the post office at the who
partners with the State Department to
issue passports. If I'm trying to open an
account online and there's a legal or
regulatory requirement that they need to
know who I am, why can't I ask the DMV or
the State Department to vouch for me? That
idea that we should start to give people
the ability to ask government to provide
this to them as a service in a way that
actually is secure and privacy enhancing,
that's really what we're calling for. So I
mentioned before we published a policy
blueprint at the end of 2022. We published
one specifically for state policymakers. I
hauled a bunch of them over in my suitcase
this morning and they're in a stack
downstairs if you'd like to grab one. But
I think my final message would be for
those of you who are engaging on the
policy side of this, we'd love to work
with you. So please don't be shy about
reaching out. You know, our goal, look,
the reason our members are all funding
this effort is because they want to have
an organization that can engage and
collaborate constructively on getting
these issues thought through properly and,
you know, get good outcomes for everybody.
So appreciate the invite again and look
forward to talking to you. Thank you.
Thank you.